Guide to the Washington State University Department of Anthropology Records 1964-1976
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Washington State University Department of Anthropology Records
1964-1976
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 59
Washington State University. Department of Anthropology
0.5 Linear feet of shelf space 1 Boxes
The records of the Washington State University Department of Anthropology includes reports, proposals, materials related to the graduate program, departmental minutes, and an accreditation report.
Anthropology courses at Washington State University originally fell under the department of Sociology, in the college of Arts and Sciences. In 1963, Anthropology became its own department. Through the years the department has had a number of homes on campus, from Commons Hall to Johnson Tower, and finally to the current building in College Hall, which was renovated in 1983 to house both the department and the Anthropology Research Lab (Center for Northwest Anthropology).
The records of the Washington State University Department of Anthropology includes reports, proposals, materials related to the graduate program, departmental minutes, and an accreditation report.
The departmental administration records (Series 1), date from 1964 through 1976, and consists of developmental proposals dealing with the field schools, archeology, social anthropology, sociology, and the budget. Also included in the series are materials related to the graduate program, departmental minutes, and an accreditation report.
The excavation projects records (Series 2), date from 1968 through 1974, and deal with the Marmes and the Ozette projects. Included are reports and proposals as well as correspondence involving Richard Daughtery (Department Chairman), Roald Fryxell (Professor of Anthropology), Charles Fred Bohannan (National Park Service Archeologist), and Gerald Grosso (Project Director). Substantial correspondence is directed to legislators and Congressmen in search of support for the projects.
The records of the Department of Anthropology are organized into two series, each arranged alphabetically by subject.
This collection is open and available for research use.
The records were transferred to the WSU University Archives in August 1977 (UA 77-30).
Washington State University Department of Anthropology Records, 1949-1989 (Archives 321)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Washington State University. Department of Anthropology -- Records and correspondence; Washington State University. Department of Sociology and Anthropology -- Records and correspondence
Anthropology -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Archives
Anthropology; Colleges and Universities; Washington (State)
- Series 1: Departmental Administration
  - Accreditation Report, 1966-1968; 15 items (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Developmental proposals
    - Archeology, 1970; 12 items (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Budget, 1969-1974; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Field School, 1970; 50 items (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - General, 1970; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Linguistics, 1970; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Outlines, 1970; 70 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Social Anthropology, 1970; 4 items (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Sociology, n.d.; 1 item (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Graduate Program, 1965-1976; 20 items (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1964-1965; 7 items (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Series 2: Excavation Projects
  - Marmes Project, 1968-1974; 135 items (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Ozette Project Correspondence, 1970-1972; 55 items (Box 1, Folder 13-15)
  - Ozette Proposals, 1972-1973; 12 items (Box 1, Folder 16)